[
    {
        "Question":"Teratology of Fallot is characterized by which one of the following malformations?",
        "Option 1":"Aortic Stenosis",
        "Option 2":"Atrial septal defects",
        "Option 3":"Hypertrophy of left ventricle",
        "Option 4":"Pulmonary stenosis",
        "Option 5":"Transposition of great vessels",
        "Correct Answer":"Pulmonary stenosis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"In the fetal circulation, the majority of blood passing from the inferior vena cava into the  right atrium subsequently passes next into which one of the following?",
        "Option 1":"Aorta",
        "Option 2":"Left atrium",
        "Option 3":"left ventricle",
        "Option 4":"pulmonary artery",
        "Option 5":"Right ventricle",
        "Correct Answer":"Left atrium"
    },
    {
        "Question":"After the nurse cut the umbilical cord. Which of the following structure will not contain  oxygenated blood anymore?",
        "Option 1":"Ductus arteriosus",
        "Option 2":"ductus venosus",
        "Option 3":"portal vein",
        "Option 4":"umbilical artery",
        "Option 5":"hepatic artery",
        "Correct Answer":"ductus venosus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 2 month old neonate with patent ductus arteriosus and left sternum murmur heard on his chest, what about this anomaly?",
        "Option 1":"Shunt from right atrium",
        "Option 2":"Shunt to left atrium",
        "Option 3":"Shunt to pulmonary artery",
        "Option 4":"Shunt to aorta",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Shunt to pulmonary artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"8 years with fatigue when playing several times. After examination, harsh systolic murmur below left clavicle is heard. What is your diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"ASD",
        "Option 2":"VSD",
        "Option 3":"PDA",
        "Option 4":"Overriding of aorta",
        "Option 5":"Coarctation of aorta",
        "Correct Answer":"PDA"
    },
    {
        "Question":"High Ventricular septum defect embryology mainly from which of the following?",
        "Option 1":"Osteum premium",
        "Option 2":"Osteum premium",
        "Option 3":"Foramen ovale",
        "Option 4":"Peri-membranous",
        "Option 5":"Muscular part",
        "Correct Answer":"Peri-membranous"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is embryology of floor of foramen ovale?",
        "Option 1":"Septum premium",
        "Option 2":"Osteum premium",
        "Option 3":"Septum secondum",
        "Option 4":"Membranous part of VSD",
        "Option 5":"Bulbar cordis",
        "Correct Answer":"Septum premium"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following structure is not from foregut but take blood supply from coeliac artery?",
        "Option 1":"Esophagus",
        "Option 2":"Pylorus of Stomach",
        "Option 3":"Spleen",
        "Option 4":"Liver hepatocytes",
        "Option 5":"Pancreas",
        "Correct Answer":"Spleen"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male child always his urination is up due to presence of urethral opening on the dorsal surface of penis and diagnosed as epispedias, what is the embryological cause of epispedias?",
        "Option 1":"Cloaca",
        "Option 2":"Urogenital tubercle",
        "Option 3":"Urethral fold",
        "Option 4":"Genital swelling",
        "Option 5":"Cloacal membrane",
        "Correct Answer":"Urogenital tubercle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"There is a tumor on the proximal part of urachus on top of urinary bladder. What is the pathology of that tumor?",
        "Option 1":"Transitional cell carcinoma",
        "Option 2":"Squamous cell carcinoma",
        "Option 3":"Adenocarcinoma",
        "Option 4":"Sarcoma",
        "Option 5":"myofibroma",
        "Correct Answer":"Adenocarcinoma"
    },
    {
        "Question":"hypospadias is a congenital anomaly of the penile urethra, The underlying cause Is  mal-development of which of the following structures?",
        "Option 1":"Urogenital sinus",
        "Option 2":"Genital tubercle",
        "Option 3":"Mesonephros",
        "Option 4":"Genital folds",
        "Option 5":"Mullerian duct",
        "Correct Answer":"Genital folds"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the associated anomaly with hypospadias?",
        "Option 1":"Ectopia vesica",
        "Option 2":"Undescended testis",
        "Option 3":"Imperforate anus",
        "Option 4":"TOF",
        "Option 5":"Malrotation",
        "Correct Answer":"Undescended testis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Embryonic failure to develop caudal portion of Metanephros leads to what  abnormality in the newborn?",
        "Option 1":"Kidney",
        "Option 2":"Ureter",
        "Option 3":"Bladder",
        "Option 4":"Seminal vesicle",
        "Option 5":"Prostate",
        "Correct Answer":"Kidney"
    },
    {
        "Question":"14 years old child with ectopic right kidney. Where is the adrenal gand most likely to  be located?",
        "Option 1":"Usual position",
        "Option 2":"contralateral site",
        "Option 3":"pelvis",
        "Option 4":"over the kidney",
        "Option 5":"in the spleen",
        "Correct Answer":"Usual position"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Infant has bilateral renal cysts with abnormality in renal calydial system. Which  developmental abnormality causes this anomaly?",
        "Option 1":"Abnormal fusion of metanephros with mesonephric duct",
        "Option 2":"Abnormal fusion of metanephros with pronephros",
        "Option 3":"Abnormal fusion of metanephros with pronephros",
        "Option 4":"Abnormal formation of metanephros",
        "Option 5":"Abnormal formation of mesonephric duct",
        "Correct Answer":"Abnormal fusion of metanephros with mesonephric duct"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 3-day old neonate had abnormal meconium stain in the infra-umbilical part of the  diaper. What is the most accepted diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Patent vitello-intestinal duct",
        "Option 2":"Patent urachus",
        "Option 3":"Patent processes vaginalis",
        "Option 4":"Patent ductus arteriosus",
        "Option 5":"Patent foramen ovale",
        "Correct Answer":"Patent vitello-intestinal duct"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following serves as the axis of gut rotation during development and  rotation of gut?",
        "Option 1":"Superior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 2":"Inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 3":"Celiac trunk",
        "Option 4":"Median sacral artery",
        "Option 5":"Umbilical vessels",
        "Correct Answer":"Superior mesenteric artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Urachus is remnant the connect urinary bladder to umbilicus. urachus when obliterated it convert to which of the following structures?",
        "Option 1":"Median umbilical Ligament",
        "Option 2":"Medial umbilical ligament",
        "Option 3":"Lateral umbilical ligament",
        "Option 4":"Ligament teres",
        "Option 5":"Ligamentous venosus",
        "Correct Answer":"Median umbilical Ligament"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male child presented by passage of meconium form her vagina and diagnosed as  recto-vaginal fistula. What is the embryological cause of vagino-rectal fistula?",
        "Option 1":"Vitello intestinal tract",
        "Option 2":"Urachus",
        "Option 3":"Cloaca",
        "Option 4":"Mesonephric duct",
        "Option 5":"Metanephric duct",
        "Correct Answer":"Cloaca"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Urinary bladder is derived from which of the following structures?",
        "Option 1":"Allantois",
        "Option 2":"Urogenital sinus",
        "Option 3":"Vitello intestinal duct",
        "Option 4":"Genital fold",
        "Option 5":"Genital tubercle",
        "Correct Answer":"Urogenital sinus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Neonate has bladder opening on anterior abdominal wall called bladder extrophy  which mainly associated with which anomaly?",
        "Option 1":"Dorsal surface opening of meatus",
        "Option 2":"Ventral surface opening of meatus",
        "Option 3":"Duodenal atresla",
        "Option 4":"Tracheo-esophageal fistula",
        "Option 5":"Annular pancreas",
        "Correct Answer":"Dorsal surface opening of meatus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following structure is remnant of embryonic notochord?",
        "Option 1":"Nucleus pulposus",
        "Option 2":"Spinal cord",
        "Option 3":"Annulus fibrosus",
        "Option 4":"Spina meninges",
        "Option 5":"Sclerotome",
        "Correct Answer":"Nucleus pulposus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Neonate has sacral hemi vertebra. Hemi-vertebra is due to defect in growth of which  part of the followings?",
        "Option 1":"Ectoderm",
        "Option 2":"Mesoderm",
        "Option 3":"Notochord",
        "Option 4":"Endoderm",
        "Option 5":"Neural tube",
        "Correct Answer":"Mesoderm"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the 1st site for haematopoiesis in embryonic life?",
        "Option 1":"Yolk sac",
        "Option 2":"Spleen",
        "Option 3":"Liver",
        "Option 4":"Bone marrow",
        "Option 5":"Thymus",
        "Correct Answer":"Yolk sac"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 2 days newborn was found to have a spinal cord anomaly. There is a sac protruding from his back containing CSF and spinal cord. Which of the following is the cause of this anomaly?",
        "Option 1":"Failure of fusion of neural tube",
        "Option 2":"Failure of fusion of notochord",
        "Option 3":"Failure of fusion of neural crest",
        "Option 4":"Failure of migration of ganglion cells",
        "Option 5":"Failure of formation of ganglion cells",
        "Correct Answer":"Failure of fusion of neural tube"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Patent ductus arteriosus (PDA) is a congenital heart disease formed from which  branchial arch?",
        "Option 1":"1st arch",
        "Option 2":"2nd arch",
        "Option 3":"3rd arch",
        "Option 4":"4th  arch",
        "Option 5":"6th arch",
        "Correct Answer":"6th arch"
    },
    {
        "Question":"From which part the tympanic space is derived from?",
        "Option 1":"1st pouch",
        "Option 2":"1\" cleft",
        "Option 3":"2nd  deft",
        "Option 4":"2nd  arch",
        "Option 5":"Cervical sinus",
        "Correct Answer":"1st pouch"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Inferior parathyroid gland develops from which embryological structure of the  following?",
        "Option 1":"1st pharyngeal pouch",
        "Option 2":"2nd pharyngeal pouch",
        "Option 3":"3rd pharyngeal pouch",
        "Option 4":"4th  pharyngeal pouch",
        "Option 5":"6th  pharyngeal arch",
        "Correct Answer":"3rd pharyngeal pouch"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the nerve supply for muscles derived from the 2nd brachial arch?",
        "Option 1":"Mandibular of trigeminal nerve",
        "Option 2":"Facial nerve",
        "Option 3":"Glossopharyngeal nerve",
        "Option 4":"Superior laryngeal nerve",
        "Option 5":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve",
        "Correct Answer":"Facial nerve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"the right and left pulmonary arteries are derived from which of the following embryological branchial arches?",
        "Option 1":"Second branchial arch",
        "Option 2":"Third branchial arch",
        "Option 3":"Fourth branchial arch",
        "Option 4":"Fifth branchial arch",
        "Option 5":"Sixth branchial arch",
        "Correct Answer":"Sixth branchial arch"
    },
    {
        "Question":"The facial nerve derived from which branchial arch?",
        "Option 1":"1st",
        "Option 2":"2nd",
        "Option 3":"3rd",
        "Option 4":"4th",
        "Option 5":"6th",
        "Correct Answer":"2nd"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male child consulted to pediatric surgeon for unilateral left cleft lip. This anomaly Is due  to failure of fusion of which processes?",
        "Option 1":"Maxillary process and medial nasal process",
        "Option 2":"Maxillary process and lateral nasal process",
        "Option 3":"Frontonasal process",
        "Option 4":"Palatine processes",
        "Option 5":"Maxillary processes",
        "Correct Answer":"Maxillary process and medial nasal process"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male child consulted to pediatric surgeon for cleft palate. This anomaly Is due to failure  of fusion of which processes?",
        "Option 1":"Frontonasal",
        "Option 2":"Maxillary",
        "Option 3":"Palatal shelves",
        "Option 4":"Lateral nasal",
        "Option 5":"Medial nasal",
        "Correct Answer":"Palatal shelves"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A boy presents with syndactyl (Webber Finger), What is the most likely cause for this  condition?",
        "Option 1":"Down syndrome",
        "Option 2":"Achondroplasia",
        "Option 3":"Due to Extensive Skin Between His Finger",
        "Option 4":"Due to lose skin between his finger",
        "Option 5":"Failure of apoptosis",
        "Correct Answer":"Failure of apoptosis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Neonate 1 day presented by cyanosis. Pediatric cardiologist made an echo and diagnosed  having one of the cyanotic heart diseases. Which of the following is this anomaly?",
        "Option 1":"Fallot of tetralogy",
        "Option 2":"Transposition of great arteries",
        "Option 3":"Ventricular septal defect",
        "Option 4":"Patent ductus arteriosus",
        "Option 5":"Atrial septal defect",
        "Correct Answer":"Transposition of great arteries"
    },
    {
        "Question":"36. A 2-day old baby presents with increasing respiratory distress. He was born at term by  normal vaginal delivery. On examination he has cyanosis of the lower limbs and marked respiratory in drawing of the chest His femoral pulses are absent bilaterally and he has  been anuria for the last 2 hours. Pulse rate is 140beats\/minute, regular, and his blood  pressure is 60\/30 mmHg in both upper limbs. What is the most likety diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Hypoplastic left heart syndrome",
        "Option 2":"Interrupted aortic arch",
        "Option 3":"Pulmonary atresia and ventricular septal defect",
        "Option 4":"Transposition of the great arteries",
        "Option 5":"Patent ductus arteriosus",
        "Correct Answer":"Interrupted aortic arch"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A urologist notices an evident slit on the dorsal surface of the penis in a 1-day newborn  baby. This anomaly is often associated with which of the following conditions?",
        "Option 1":"Horseshoe kidney",
        "Option 2":"Renal agenesis",
        "Option 3":"Bladder exstrophy",
        "Option 4":"Polycystic kidney",
        "Option 5":"Bladder diverticulum",
        "Correct Answer":"Bladder exstrophy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Neonate presented by urinary retention and bilateral back pressure on the kidneys. What  is the congenital anomaly responsible for that?",
        "Option 1":"PUJO",
        "Option 2":"Ureteric regurge",
        "Option 3":"Posterior urethral valve",
        "Option 4":"Bladder cancer",
        "Option 5":"Urethral stenosis",
        "Correct Answer":"Posterior urethral valve"
    },
    {
        "Question":"In fetal circulation, how will the blood passes from right atrium to left atrium through?",
        "Option 1":"Ductus venosus",
        "Option 2":"Ductus arteriosus",
        "Option 3":"Foramen ovale",
        "Option 4":"Pulmonary artery",
        "Option 5":"VSD",
        "Correct Answer":"Foramen ovale"
    },
    {
        "Question":"20 years old man presented by cystic swelling on anterior surface of sternomastoid and diagnosed as branchial cyst. The branchial cyst derived from which pharyngeal arch?",
        "Option 1":"First",
        "Option 2":"Second",
        "Option 3":"Third",
        "Option 4":"Fourth",
        "Option 5":"Six",
        "Correct Answer":"Second"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A mother noticed a sinus anterior to sternomastoid on neck of her child. From which  branchial cleft derived this cervical sinus?",
        "Option 1":"1st",
        "Option 2":"2nd",
        "Option 3":"3rd",
        "Option 4":"4th",
        "Option 5":"5th",
        "Correct Answer":"2nd"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 2 days newborn was found to have a spinal cord anomaly. There is a sac protruding from  his back contalning CSF only. What Is the most likely dlagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Spina bifida occulta",
        "Option 2":"Meningomyelocele",
        "Option 3":"Meningocele",
        "Option 4":"Spinal canal stenosis",
        "Option 5":"Sacrococcygeal teratoma",
        "Correct Answer":"Meningocele"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 3 days newborn was found to have a spinal cord anomaly. There is a sac protruding from  his back containing CSF and spinal nerves. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Spina bifida occulta",
        "Option 2":"Meningomyelocele",
        "Option 3":"Meningocele",
        "Option 4":"Spinal canal stenosis",
        "Option 5":"Sacrococcygeal teratoma",
        "Correct Answer":"Meningomyelocele"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Congenital anomaly results from failure of fusion of neural crest which migrates to the back without protrusion of meninges or spinal nerves. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Spina bifida occulta",
        "Option 2":"Meningomyelocele",
        "Option 3":"Meningocele",
        "Option 4":"Spinal canal stenosis",
        "Option 5":"Sacrococcygeal teratoma",
        "Correct Answer":"Spina bifida occulta"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What did two Lateral ligaments passing from umbilicus carry during fetal period?",
        "Option 1":"Deoxygenated blood from placenta to fetus",
        "Option 2":"Deoxygenated blood from fetus to placenta",
        "Option 3":"Oxygenated blood from fetus to placenta",
        "Option 4":"Oxygenated blood from placenta to fetus",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Deoxygenated blood from fetus to placenta"
    },
    {
        "Question":"The ligament from umbilical to right upper quadrant carried which vessel in fetal life?",
        "Option 1":"Ductus venous",
        "Option 2":"Ductus arteriosus",
        "Option 3":"Umbilical artery",
        "Option 4":"Umbilical vein",
        "Option 5":"IVC",
        "Correct Answer":"Umbilical vein"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Pregnant woman has fetus 22 weeks in follow up clinic, obstetrician noticed his bowel covered by  sac and his husband is paediatrician. What will you tell him about the physiological time in weeks  for bowel return to abdomen in intra uterine life?",
        "Option 1":"4 weeks",
        "Option 2":"8 weeks",
        "Option 3":"12 weeks",
        "Option 4":"22 weeks",
        "Option 5":"24 weeks",
        "Correct Answer":"12 weeks"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Ventricular septum defect embryology mainly from which of the following?",
        "Option 1":"Endocardial cushion",
        "Option 2":"Sinus venosus",
        "Option 3":"Truncus Arteriosus",
        "Option 4":"Coronary sinus",
        "Option 5":"Septum primum",
        "Correct Answer":"Endocardial cushion"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Vitello intestinal (omphalomesentric) duct connect yolk sac to which part of the gut in the embryo?",
        "Option 1":"Foregut",
        "Option 2":"Midgut",
        "Option 3":"Hindgut",
        "Option 4":"Urachus",
        "Option 5":"Stomach",
        "Correct Answer":"Midgut"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the definition of congenital total absent of one limb?",
        "Option 1":"Ameila",
        "Option 2":"Oligodactyly",
        "Option 3":"Phocomelia",
        "Option 4":"Syndactyl",
        "Option 5":"Athelia",
        "Correct Answer":"Ameila"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Child has cleft palate. From which embryological origin this happened?",
        "Option 1":"1st  arch",
        "Option 2":"2nd  arch",
        "Option 3":"3rd arch",
        "Option 4":"4th  arch",
        "Option 5":"6th  arch",
        "Correct Answer":"1st  arch"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Child has urethra ventral opening on his penis. what is the proper management?",
        "Option 1":"Hypospadias surgery",
        "Option 2":"Epispadias surgery",
        "Option 3":"Meatoplasty",
        "Option 4":"Circumcision",
        "Option 5":"Dorsal slit",
        "Correct Answer":"Hypospadias surgery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"The 2nd branchial arch give rise to",
        "Option 1":"Anterior belly of digastric",
        "Option 2":"Lesser horn of hyoid bone",
        "Option 3":"Incus",
        "Option 4":"Malleus",
        "Option 5":"Mylohyoid",
        "Correct Answer":"Lesser horn of hyoid bone"
    },
    {
        "Question":"The first branchial arch develops during the 4th and 5th week in utero as a series of  mesodermal out pouching on either side of developing pharynx. The first branchial arch  give rise to",
        "Option 1":"Lie between 1\" branchial groove and proctodium",
        "Option 2":"Give rise to medial part of upper lip",
        "Option 3":"Give rise to muscles of facial expression",
        "Option 4":"Give rise to anterior part of tongue",
        "Option 5":"Give rise to stapes",
        "Correct Answer":"Give rise to anterior part of tongue"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 1-year-old baby boy is brought into hospital looking cyanotic, short of breath, and failing  to thrive. He is admitted and investigated for congenital cyanotic heart disease. Which of  the following congenital heart conditions does not typically cause cyanosis?",
        "Option 1":"Atrial septal defect",
        "Option 2":"Right ventricular outfilow tract obstruction",
        "Option 3":"Tetralogy of Fallot",
        "Option 4":"Transposition of the great arteries",
        "Option 5":"Total anomalous pulmonary venous drainage",
        "Correct Answer":"Atrial septal defect"
    },
    {
        "Question":"The sinus venosus is large quadrangular cavity located between the two vena cava vessels In embryonic human heart. In adult heart, sinus venosus give rise to",
        "Option 1":"Aortic vestibule of left ventricle",
        "Option 2":"Coronary sinus",
        "Option 3":"Fossa ovalis",
        "Option 4":"Trabeculated part of right ventricle",
        "Option 5":"Trabeculated part of right atrium",
        "Correct Answer":"Coronary sinus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Derivatives of the hindgut are typically supplied by the:",
        "Option 1":"Celiac artery",
        "Option 2":"Ductus arteriosus",
        "Option 3":"Inferior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 4":"Superior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 5":"Umbilical artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Inferior mesenteric artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"An upper gastrointestinal surgeon dissects around the oesophageal hiatus of the diaphragm during oesophagectomy for an early oesophagogastric tumor. Which of the following statements is correct regarding the thoracic dlaphragm?",
        "Option 1":"It has an oesophageal hiatus at vertebral level T8",
        "Option 2":"It has a central tendon that transmits the right phrenic nerve",
        "Option 3":"It is partly derived from the pleuro peritoneal membrane",
        "Option 4":"It originates partly form the body of the sternum",
        "Option 5":"The intercostal nerves supply it with accessory motor innervation",
        "Correct Answer":"It is partly derived from the pleuro peritoneal membrane"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the most common associated anomaly with horseshoe kidney?",
        "Option 1":"Pelviureteric junction obstruction",
        "Option 2":"Duodenal atresia",
        "Option 3":"Hurshsprung disease",
        "Option 4":"Malrotation",
        "Option 5":"Esophageal atresia",
        "Correct Answer":"Pelviureteric junction obstruction"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Horseshoe kidney isthmus at which level?",
        "Option 1":"T12-L3 vertebrae",
        "Option 2":"L3-L5 vertebrae",
        "Option 3":"At level of superior mesenteric artery",
        "Option 4":"At level of median sacral artery",
        "Option 5":"T11-L1 vertebrae",
        "Correct Answer":"L3-L5 vertebrae"
    }
]